<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Víctor Ávila</title>
    <link>https://avilapa.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Víctor Ávila</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>All rights reserved - 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 27 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://avilapa.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Custom Engine: Physically Based Rendering</title>
      <link>https://avilapa.github.io/post/custom-engine-pbr/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://avilapa.github.io/post/custom-engine-pbr/</guid>
      <description>Index  Background Physically Based Rendering  Introduction Physically Based Shading Image Based Lighting Merging  Atmospheric Scattering  Rayleigh Scattering Mie Scattering Phase Functions  References  Background Physically Based Rendering is not a technique, but a collection of graphics techniques aiming to achieve results as close as possible to the physical world. This means that these techniques are highly based on real world physics light behaviour formulas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Custom Engine: Postprocessing</title>
      <link>https://avilapa.github.io/post/custom-engine-postprocessing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://avilapa.github.io/post/custom-engine-postprocessing/</guid>
      <description>The postprocessing pipeline and some of its postprocessing effects in my custom rendering engine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Custom OpenGL C&#43;&#43; Engine</title>
      <link>https://avilapa.github.io/render-engine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2006 03:45:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://avilapa.github.io/render-engine/</guid>
      <description>The Engine This is an OpenGL and C++ rendering engine I made in my final HND year at ESAT Valencia for the graphics programming subject. Its main features are the following:
 Multithreaded agnostical graphics API Component oriented engine Physically Based Rendering techniques:  Material pipeline (PBS, Metallic/Roughness workflow) Image Based Lighting (Radiance and Irradiance environment mapping) Atmospheric Scattering (Rayleigh and Mie Scattering)  GLTF model loading Postprocessing Pipeline:  Screen Space Ambient Occlusion (SSAO) Bloom Light Scattering (God Rays) Shadow Mapping Fast Approximate Anti-Aliasing (FXAA) Lens Distortion (with Grain, Vignette, Color Aberration) Tonemapping and multiple one-pass filters  Procedural generation of infinite voxel worlds UI integration (ImGui) Sound integration (OpenAL) Physics integration (Bullet Physics)  Blog posts  Custom Engine: Physically Based Rendering The physically based approach used for my custom rendering engine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fuel Renegades</title>
      <link>https://avilapa.github.io/fuel-renegades/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2006 03:45:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://avilapa.github.io/fuel-renegades/</guid>
      <description>Blog posts  Framerate independent physics in UE4 How to achieve physics framerate independence in UE4 and how to correctly use substepping. Víctor Ávila</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About me</title>
      <link>https://avilapa.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://avilapa.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>I am a videogames programming student in Valencia, Spain. Currently I am on my third year of ESAT, developing Fuel Renegades, an Unreal Engine 4 racing multiplayer game with a small student team, Modular Souls. I am very interested in graphics programming, so at the moment I am also building a small real-time engine in C++ and OpenGL named UPyDK. I have plans of obtaining my bachelor degree next year in Sheffield Hallam University</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>